YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 10. Audiovisual Materials
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. VIDEOTAPES
  - Videotapes--USE COPIES, [Use copies are numbered with the box and tape number of the original videotapes]
    - From box 1088 folder 18 - "The Beacon," Brooklyn School District #18 program hosted by Dr. Harvey Gunn. Discussion of important issues in education today with Gwendolyn Baker in her capacity as NY City School Board President, VHS, also Learning Tech Fair XI 1st Place Winner, 1991 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1088 folder 19 - "By Faith: Christian Students Among the Cloud of Witnesses," documentary history of Christian student activism, used YWCA sources. Copyright Friendship Press, VHS, 1991 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1089 folder 14-32nd National Convention (Atlanta 15-19 May 1991), Sylvia Unzueta, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1089 folder 15-32nd National Convention (Atlanta 15-19 May 1991), Ann Stallard Acceptance Speech, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1090 folder 2 - "Join Us," 30 second Public Service Announcement, Phyllis Kerle Associates, Umatic and VHS, 24 Jun 1991 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1090 folder 18 - "It's a Hit!" YWCA of the USA and US Field Hockey Association, promotional video about field hockey, VHS, Sept 1991 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1091 folder 9 - "Give It a Shot!," National Girls Tennis Program promotional video, 1992, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1091 folder 11 - EEOC v. YWCA of Tucson, Presentation by Chris Carty and Glendora Putnam distributed to Community Associations with information about the consent decree, 1992, VHS 1989 (Box 1112)
    - From box 1092 folder 15 - Project Redesign, presentation for National Board meeting, 15 May 1992, Edited version, with update by Ann Stallard, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1094 folder 4 - Mid-Triennial Conferences, Apr 1993, Opening and Closing photo montages with music, Spring 1993, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1094 folder 15-135th Anniversary historical slides, October 1993, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1094 folder 21 - YWCA Retirement Fund: "Guardian Spirits", 1 Feb 1994, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1095 folder 10 - Public Service Announcements produced by Louis London (featuring YWCA historical photographs), Feb-Nov 1994, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1095 folder 19 - "Putting Women First for 135 Years," 18 minute video for 135th Anniversary, Apr 1994, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1097 folder 2 - World YWCA Centenary Service, Cathedral Church of St. John and St. Peter [Washington National Cathedral], 16 Oct 1994, Edited, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1097 folder 7 - "Talk it Over" show on Lifetime Television, program on violence featuring Project Protect at the YWCA of Eastern Union County, New Jersey, 1995, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1097 folder 11 - Strategic Planning Initiative, "Strategic Planning Forum '95, Round 2," videotape distributed to Host Associations for use if weather prevented national leadership from getting to the Forum, produced on 11 Feb using footage from 6 Feb Forum in Phoenix, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1098 folder 16 - Women's Vote Project '96 Public Service Announcement "Empowerment," 17 Oct 1995, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1099 folder 16 - "The First YWCA Week Without Violence," re the 1995 campaign, 1996, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1099 folder 19 - Women's Vote Project '96 short television spot for Iowa, Lifetime Television, circa 1996, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1099 folder 23 - "The Imperative is Now! Legacy of a Movement," Convention preparation video, Apr 1996, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1100 folder 16 to 20 - 34th National Convention (Jun 1996), EP tapes, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1100 folder 20a - Mission Plenary: Panel on Heterosexism, 7 Jun, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1100 folder 28 - President Bill Clinton Public Service Announcements for Week Without Violence, Redesign, 30 Sep 1996, Original and re-edited versions, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1100 folder 30 - USA Network Public Service Announcements for "Erase the Hate" campaign, YWCA Week Without Violence, 6-12 Oct 1996, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1101 folder 2 - Nickelodeon Television "Big Help" coverage of the Presidents' Summit for America's Future, Apr 1997, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1101 folder 7 - "The Imperative is Now: A Panel Discussion on Race and Race Relations," final version, 28 Jan 1998, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1101 folder 8 - "The National Hate Test," USA Television special premiering in conjunction with the National Erase the Hate and Eliminate Racism Day, 30 Apr 1998, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1101 folder 11 - YWCA National Board's Recommended National Dues Formula, Jul 1998, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1101 folder 21 - "Hidden Victims: Children of Domestic Violence," Lifetime Television program with segment on Annapolis and Anne Arundel County YWCA program, 6 Nov 2000, VHS (Box 1112)
    - ENCOREplus Program, Training at Leadership Development Center, n.d.
      - From box 1102 folder 4 and 5 - Barbara Haber, Psychosocial Aspects of Breast Cancer, VHS (Box 1112)
      - From box 1102 folder 6 and 7 - Fran Liggett, Group Dynamics, VHS (Box 1112)
      - From box 1102 folder 8, 9, and 10 - Joan Wagman, Budgeting and Administration of ENCORE Program, VHS (Box 1112)
    - From box 1999 - "100 Years of Women" a Lifetime Television documentary, 1999, [copyrighted and commercially available-no preservation copy kept] (Box 1112)